我是黑鸟  请说出你的身份
This is Blackbird. Identification.
代号223  我的身份暴露了
Designate 2-2-3. I am blown. I am blown.
你的电话未经授权  223
This call is unauthorized, 2-2-3.
这条线路不安全
This line is not secure.
安全屋到底在哪
Where is the safe house?
无可奉告  223  你知道规矩的
Negative, 2-2-3. You know the rules.
你我之间有种感觉  没有东西能够改变
We've got something between us nothing can change.
我想你说的挺对  沃尔特
Oh, well, I suppose you're right in a way, Walter.
你不接电话吗
Aren't you gonna answer that?
不
Nope.
你也不许接
Oh-- and neither are you.
你这又是在躲谁呢
Who are you hiding from now?
吉娜
Gina.
忘了给赡养费了吗
Forget an alimony payment?
不是  这次她不是以前妻的身份打给我的
No, this time she's not calling as my ex-wife.
而是以出版商的身份
She's calling as my publisher.
我新书的手稿应该在昨天就上交了
The first draft of my new manuscript was due yesterday,
但我还没写完
and I haven't finished.
-为什么  -创作情绪不佳
- Why not? - Haven't felt like writing.
而且  我对书中角色走向
And besides, I don't think I'm entirely happy
不是很满意
with where my characters are going.
那就改呗
Well... change them.
正有此打算  你在这干嘛呢
Working on it. What are you doing here?
我以为你今晚要去
I thought you had an
威廉斯镇戏剧节试镜呢
audition for Williamstown tonight.
没错  我是来拿我那件幸运小外套的
I do. Just came to pick up my lucky blouse.
我进啦
Aah! I got in!
-我进啦  -很好嘛
- I got in! - Oh, good.
我的天呐  你进啦  太棒了  真不敢相...
Oh, my god. You got in. That's amazing! I can't b--
我不...你进什么了
I don't--what-- what did you get into?
普林斯顿大学为高中生准备的暑期项目
Princeton's summer program for high school students.
你不是在候补名单里吗
I thought you got wait-listed.
有人退出了
Someone just canceled,
我们得尽快给他们把学费寄过去
but we have to send them a deposit ASAP,
因为这项目本周末就开始了
because it starts this weekend.
这周末
This weekend?
我知道我们有计划了  但是
I know we had plans,but--
不止是计划
not just plans--
那可是阵亡将士纪念日  在汉普顿
Memorial day, the Hamptons,
我们每年一度的"盛夏开幕"周啊
our annual "Kick off the summer" week.
而且  我搞到了一些违禁烟花
I mean, I got the illegal fireworks,
你喜欢的那种  有银色火光的
the kind you like, the ones with the silver starbursts.
老爸  这可是普林斯顿
Dad, it's Princeton.
我真不敢相信你会放弃违禁烟花
I can't believe you would blow off illegal fireworks
就为了提前开始无聊的顶级教育
for a lousy head start at a top-notch education.
我知道  我大煞风景
I know. I'm a huge disappointment.
好了  还有一堆表等着你签名呢
Now there are a bunch of forms you need to sign,
我把其他的填完就给你签名
and I'll fill the rest out for you later.
等等
Whoa, whoa, whoa. Hey.
这上面说宿舍是男女混宿的
It says here that the, uh, the dorms are coed.
对啊  大学嘛
Yeah, it's college.
才不是  这只是个针对高中生的
No, it's a summer program for high school students
大学暑期项目
at a college.
根据这上面所说  你那栋楼的一半人
According to this, half the kids in your building
都是十六七岁的男生
will be 16- and 17-year-old boys.
别担心  老爸  每层楼都有一个21岁的宿管呢
Relax, dad. Each floor has a resident advisor who's 21.
也就是说管事儿的人
Oh, so the one person in charge
已经到了合法买酒的年龄了
is conveniently old enough to buy alcohol?
亲爱的  别那么老古板了
Darling, don't be such a prude.
你还记得你和全班人去意大利旅行那次吗
Remember that trip you took to Italy with your class?
你当时还没有阿丽克西斯大呢
You were younger than Alexis is now.
老妈  如果你知道那趟旅行中发生了什么
Mother, if you had any idea what happened on that trip,
你永远都不会让我再离家半步的
you would've never let me leave the house again.
有些时候  知道的越少越好
Sometimes, the less you know, the better.
你还有本小说要写呢
You have a novel to finish.
卡塞尔
It's Castle.
就像是传统的节日
It's kinda like a tradition--
篝火啦  烤棉花糖啦
You know, bonfires, roasting marshmallows,
讲鬼故事啦  熬夜啦
telling ghost stories, sleeping late.
从她五岁起我们一直如此
We've done it since she was 5.
听起来不错  老实说  蛮神奇的
Sounds nice. Kinda magical, actually.
没错  你也应该一起来玩儿
Yeah, you know what? You should come.
就在海边  还有私家泳池
Oh, it's right on the ocean. There's a secluded pool.
你可以躺那  晒晒太阳
You could lay out, work on your tan.
卡塞尔  为了一睹我的泳装造型
Wow, Castle, you're working really hard
你还真是不遗余力啊
to see me in a swimsuit.
如果你不喜欢穿泳装的话
If you are not comfortable in a swimsuit,
你可以裸泳哦
you can just skinny-dip.
死者是白人男性
The vic's a white male,
胸部多处中枪
multiple gunshot wounds to the chest.
大约一小时前发现他的
Found him about an hour ago.
抢劫吗
Mugging?
不是  手表钱包和现金都在
Nah. He still has his watch, wallet and cash.
还有就是幽灵般消失的子弹
Then there's the matter of the phantom bullets.
是的  他胸口一共中了五枪
Yeah, he took five to the chest.
没有弹头  没有弹壳
There are no slugs, shell casings.
凶手甚至把子弹从那些树枝里
the killer went so far as to dig his bullets out of
挖了出来
that tree branch right there.
真怪异  死者体内也没有吗
That's weird. What about in the body?
子弹全部射穿了死者身体
They're all through and throughs.
每处伤口都有子弹射出的弹孔
Exit holes on each wound.
也就是说案发后凶手清理了现场
So our doer cleaned up after himself.
往一个人胸口连开五枪之后
It takes real presence of mind
仍能保持头脑冷静
to put five bullets into a man's chest
把现场收拾干净
and then keep your cool long enough
需要相当的心理素质
to pick up after yourself.
本能反应是杀完就跑
Natural instinct is to run.
我猜我们在对付的极可能是
I would say we are most likely dealing with
一个训练有素的杀手
a highly trained assassin.
死亡时间呢
Time of death?
从尸体温度和尸斑来看
Based on temperature and lividity,
我想是在晚上十一点到凌晨一点之间
I'd say between 11:00 pm and 1:00 am.
身份呢
ID?
肖恩·卡维尔  没发现驾照
Shawn Caldwell. No driver's license,
但根据他的工作证
but according to his work ID,
他是市区一间名叫FGS公司的顾问
he was a consultant for FGS in midtown.
激流环球服务公司
"Fastwater Global Services"?
像是中情局的掩护身份
Sounds like a CIA front.
在他口袋里发现了这些
Found these in his pocket.
公司的车钥匙
Company car keys.
钥匙圈上没有住家钥匙
There's no house keys on the chain.
这里有张很普通的宾馆房卡
There's a generic hotel key card.
外地来的吗
In from out of town?
但公司地址是本地的
Except the company address is local,
他的健身会员卡也是
and so is his gym membership.
好了  让鉴证组检查现场吧
All right. Have CSU sweep the area,
再询问那些流浪者
canvass the homeless people,
看是否有人听到或看到些什么
see if anyone saw or heard anything.
俺家阳台的海景
Ocean view from my patio.
没有比这个更好的地方了
It does not get better than this.
怎么了
What's wrong?
我查了所有资料  搜遍了数据库
I tried information, our database.
甚至上网进行了搜索
I even did an internet search,
-这些人仿佛根本就不存在  -哪些人
- And it's like these guys don't even exist. - Who?
激流环球服务公司
Fastwater Global Services.
看  我就说吧  中情局的伪装
Ah! See? I told you. CIA cover.
开玩笑的  他们可能是不喜欢做广告
No. I mean, they probably just don't like to advertise.
没错  我起初也这么想
Yeah, well, I thought so as well,
所以我查了他们的地址
so I checked their address--
西43街  1747号
1747 West 43rd Str.
那是在哈德逊河里
It's in the middle of the Hudson River.
所以我又检查了他的钱包
So I went back and checked through his wallet
查看了他的证件  健身会员卡
and looked at his IDs, his gym membership,
医疗保险  甚至他的自动提款卡
health insurance, even his ATM card--
-全是假的  -你查过他的名字了吗
- They're all fakes. - You run his name?
查了  纽约以及新泽西  康涅狄格州有六个
Yeah, there's about half a dozen Shawn Caldwells
肖恩·卡维尔  但没一个吻合的
in the tristate area, and none of them are a match.
-那他的指纹呢  -我们的数据库里没有
- What about his fingerprints? - Not in our system.
-贝克特  -有什么发现
- Hey, Beckett. - Hey, what'd you guys find?
我们询问了一些昨晚
Well, we spoke to some homeless guys who were camped
在距桥几百码处露宿的流浪汉
a couple hundred yards from the overpass last night.
他们没听到或看到任何事情
They didn't see or hear anything.
几百码
Couple hundred yards?
五声枪响  怎么可能没听到
How do you not hear five gunshots?
-除非  -凶手用了消音器
- Unless... - He used a silencer.
用装了消音器的枪  杀一个故意掩藏身份的人
To kill a man who went out of the way to hide who he was?
这听起来越来越像
This is starting to sound more and more
职业杀手干的了
like a professional hit.
是啊  只有查出受害者的身份
Yeah, well, we're nowhere until we figure out
我们才能有所突破
who this guy actually is.
你们去查查公园
So why don't you guys go canvass the area
入口的区域吧  看是否能找到他的车
near the entrance to the park, see if you can find his car?
另外  把他的照片传真给本地宾馆
And fax his photo to the local hotels,
-看是否有人能认出他  -这就去
- see if anyone recognizes his face. - Right on.
你知道...
You know, I-I was...
关于杀手的说法  我是开玩笑的
I was kidding about the assassin stuff.
是蕾妮
That's Lanie.
拜托  告诉我你有发现了
Please tell me that you found something.
关于被害人的身份
Well, I found nothing that sheds light
我一无所获
on the identity of your victim,
但我发现了些线索  也许能帮你们找到凶手
But I did find something that may help with your killer.
我们知道凶手清理了犯罪现场的
We know the shooter tried to scrub the crime scene
弹道痕迹  但有一发子弹
of ballistic evidence, but one of the rounds
射中了卡维尔的肋骨  留下了线索
shattered Mr. Caldwell's rib and left this little souvenir.
-子弹碎片  -分不清枪支的口径
- A bullet fragment?  - Can't tell the caliber,
但外缘的多边形膛线
but this polygonal rifling along the outer rim
与格洛克手枪吻合
is consistent with the barrel of a Glock.
-怎么了  -这组枪击
- What?  - The grouping of the shots.
发现伤口都很紧致了吗
You see how tight they all are?
没有斑点烧痕和枪口烧伤
There's no stippling, no muzzle burns.
一定是远距离射击
The killer must have shot from a distance.
也就是说  他枪法很准
Which means he's a very good shot.
很好  谢谢
Great. Thanks.
他们找到车了
They found the car.
车是登记在联合舰队服务公司名下的
Car is registered to Allied Fleet Services,
是家汽车租赁公司
a car rental agency.
但愿他们买了保险
Oh, I hope they got the insurance option.
这车租给谁了
Who did they rent it to?
这辆车被FGS长期租用了
This particular car is on a long-term lease to FGS.
激流环球服务公司
Fastwater Global Services.
他们知道把车租给了根本不存在的公司吗
Do they know they rented their car to a company that doesn't exist?
不  这公司存在  不在纽约而已
Oh, no. It exists, just not in New York.
所有的信函  账单和工资
All correspondence, billing and payments go through
都经由一个位于开曼群岛的邮箱
a P.O Box in the Cayman Islands.
这案子越来越诡异了  在车尾箱找到这个
It gets even weirder. In the trunk, we found these.
欧元
Euros.
一共是五千元  还有
5,000 of 'em, and...
-这看起来像军方武器  -没错
- That looks military.  - Yeah.
盒子里是什么
What's in the box?
-精品钢笔  -赞
- A fancy pen. - Nice!
一个装满欧元的袋子  一把军用枪
A bag full of euros, a high-tech heater
还有个雁过无痕的神秘杀手
and a silent killer who leaves no trace...
代号223  晚上好  告密者身份已确认
Good evening, 2-2-3. Informant has been identified.
同盟方联系人会在13至15个小时内
Ally contact will meet you
在摩尔咖啡馆与你见面
at Cafe Moul in 13-15 hours
下达进一步的指令
with further instructions.
带上笔  暗号如下
Wear the pen and use the following code phrase--
"你是史蒂夫的朋友吧"
"Aren't you Steve's friend?"
答"不  史蒂夫是我兄弟"
Response,"No, Steve is my brother."
祝好运  代号223
Good luck, 2-2-3.
现在知道为什么被害人不存在了
Well, now we know why our victim doesn't exist.
他是个间谍
He's a spy.
我们联系了中情局  联邦调查局
We contacted the CIA, the FBI,
国家安全局和国土安全部
the NSA and Homeland Security.
目前为止  都否认被害人是他们的人
So far, all of them are denying that he was one of theirs.
他们当然会否认
Well, of course they're gonna deny it.
他可能从被杀的那刻起就被除名了
He was probably disavowed the moment he was killed,
使这案子史无前例的酷
making this officially the coolest case ever.
我们要怎么做  长官
So what do you want us to do, sir?
做好本职工作  在上级有其它指示前
Your job. Till someone more important tells us different,
此案作为普通的凶杀案处理
treat this like a standard homicide case.
你们去咖啡馆
You go to the cafe.
如果这个联系人跟他是盟友
If this contact of his is an ally,
他们也许会提供线索
they may be willing to talk.
我们要如何确定这个...联系人
How are we gonna identify the... contact?
假扮我们的被害人
Same way our victim was going to.
找到了
Bingo.
她
Her?
这里只有她是一个人
She's the only one here alone.
你是史蒂夫的朋友吧
Aren't you Steve's friend?
什么
Pardon?
你是史蒂夫的朋友吧
Aren't you steve's friend?
史蒂夫  不不  抱歉  我不认识史蒂夫
Steve? No, no, I'm sorry. I don't know Steve.
你确定
Are you sure?
他不是你的兄弟吗
So he's not your brother?
-离我远点  -好的
- Go away. - Okay.
-不是她  -看出来了
- Wasn't her. - Yeah, I gathered.
-你不觉得这一切有点怪吗  -怎么了
- This all feel a little odd to you? - What?
老式的间谍故事  秘密会面  暗号
The old cloak-and-dagger, secret meetings, code words--
感觉太老套了
It all feels a little old-fashioned.
我是说  为什么要亲自见面呢
I mean, why meet face-to-face
直接发一封加密邮件不就行了
when you can just send an encrypted e-mail?
有时候  就得远离喧嚣的高科技
Sometimes, you just have to do things off the grid.
说到远离喧嚣  周末度假的邀请我是认真的
Speaking of off the grid, I was serious about this weekend.
你当真邀请我去你汉普顿的住处吗
You're seriously asking me to your place in the Hamptons?
我保证不搞鬼  就是朋友一起度个假
I promise, no funny stuff. Just a friendly getaway.
很有趣的
It'd be fun.
好...不行
Yeah... no.
我还要为了生计工作呢
Y-you know, some of us have to work for a living.
-在阵亡将士纪念日?  -是啊  我已经没假了
- On Memorial Day? - Yes. I spent all of my vacation days
-都用在找新公寓上了  -嘘  嘘
- looking for a new place to live. - Shh,shh,shh.
你是史蒂夫的朋友吧
Aren't you Steve's friend?
不  史蒂夫是我的兄弟
No. Steve's my brother.
保尔  汉斯·保尔
Brauer. Hans Brauer.
-肖恩·卡维尔  -我们没时间了
- Shawn Caldwell. - We don't have much time.
目标抵达美国  但是一直在移动
The target's in country, but on the move.
去阿尔法位置寻找标志
Go to alpha location and look for the sign,
但是黑鸟要你知道
but blackbird wants you to know,
会有其他人搅局
there are other assets in play.
如果他们对你采取行动  立刻转入地下
So if they move on you, go to ground.
但是如果有机会刺杀  要行动  明白吗
But if you get a shot, take it. Understood?
明白
Understood.
等等
Wait.
我的人需要确认目标人物的名字
My people need confirmation on the target's name.
-你说什么  -目标人物的名字
- What did you say? - The target's name,
我的人需要确认
my people need confirmation.
你是谁
Who are you?
纽约警察局
NYPD!
手举起来
Hands up.
没说你  卡塞尔
Not you, Castle.
好的
Right.
你们完全不知道自己卷入了什么事件
You people have no idea what you just stepped into.
什么也不知道
No idea.
你不说我们怎么知道
Why don't you tell us?
因为你不会想要知道的
Because you don't want to know.
我看过的那些事情
The things that I've seen?
相信我
Trust me...
无知是福
Ignorance is bliss.
你为谁工作  政府吗
Who do you work for, the government?
如果不是替政府卖命  是为谁
Well, if not the government, then who?
真正的卡维尔怎么了
What happened to the real Caldwell?
-死了  -何时
- Dead. - When?
昨晚
Last night.
那意味着他们知道了
That means they know.
他们知道什么了
They know about what?
知道目标了吗
About the target?
知道你们如何刺杀了吗
About how you were going to take your shot?
你的目标是谁  汉斯
Who's your target, Hans?
在阿富汗的时候  整整三周
I spent three weeks in Afghanistan
火蚂蚁爬满了我的裆部
with fire ants crawling on my privates.
我可不认为你们礼貌而又严肃的审问
Somehow I don't think your polite-but-stern routine
会有什么结果
is gonna get you very far.
你想要问什么都可以
You can ask me whatever you want.
不过我要告诉你接下来会发生什么
But let me tell you what's gonna happen here.
再过一小会  你会接到一个电话
In just a little while, you will receive a phone call
那人官衔要比你的大得多
from someone much more important than you.
之后他们会告诉你
Then they will tell you that
这是个误会
there's been a misunderstanding,
你们会奉命放了我
and you will be instructed to release me.
你尽管很不情愿
You will do so grudgingly,
但是最终你还是要照做
but you will do so nonetheless.
你会眼睁睁的看着我遁入黑夜
And you will watch me walk out of here into the night...
再也不会见到我
Never to be seen again.
这到底是怎么回事
What the hell are we into here?
希望联邦调查局的人能有所发现
Hopefully the Feds will have more luck.
我深表怀疑
Somehow I doubt it.
至少没时间阻止他们的行动了
At least not in time to stop whatever he's planning.
贝克特
Yo, Beckett.
刚刚与卡特帝豪宾馆经理通过电话
That was the manager of the Carter Regency Hotel,
他认出了死者
says he recognized our vic.
死者两天前入住  没有退房
Guy checked in two days ago and never checked out.
安全  卡塞尔  检查柜子
Clear. Castle, check the bureau.
保险柜锁着
The safe is locked.
打开
Open it.
不管他要做什么  原计划是今天行动
Whatever he was supposed to do, it was going down today.
他打算明天结账退房
He was scheduled to check out tomorrow.
更多的身份证明
It's more IDs.
约翰·梅森  保罗·切斯基
John Mason... Paul Chenausky.
可能也是假的
Probably fake, too.
卡塞尔
Castle.
是什么
What is it?
一份秘密档案
It's a security dossier.
科菲·阿曼度
Kofi Amandul.
科菲·阿曼度是谁
Who's Kofi Amandul?
鲁瓦尼亚共和国的银行部长
The minister of banking for The Republic Of Luvania.
这是在联合国大楼门口拍摄的
These were taken in front of the U.N.
这就是目标
This is the target.
这就是他们想要杀的人
This is who they're trying to kill.
我得给国务院打电话
I have to call the state department.
我认为可以不打了
I don't think you have to.
写德里克·斯道姆的时候  我自学成了
While writing Derrick Storm, I became somewhat of
地理达人
an expert on world geography.
-你听说过鲁瓦尼亚共和国吗  -没有
- You ever heard of the republic of Luvania? - No.
是啊  我也没听过  知道原因吗
Yeah, neither have I. You know why?
因为没有这个国家
Because it doesn't exist.
我有预感科菲·阿曼度这个人也不存在
I got a feeling Kofi Amandul doesn't exist either.
他们为什么要杀一个
Then why would they try to kill someone
不存在的人呢
who doesn't exist?
我想我知道了
I think I know.
走吧
Come on.
我拿到了弹道检验的结果
So I just got back from ballistics.
死者车里发现的那把枪...
That gun that we found in the victim's car...
我猜猜  是假的
Let me guess, it's not real...
-是场游戏  -你在说什么
-It's a game. - What are you talking about?
整件事  假的身份证明
This whole thing-- the fake IDs,
档案  鲁瓦尼亚  银行部长
The dossiers, Luvania, the banking minister--
都是游戏的一部分
It's all part of a game.
拜托  别破坏游戏的规则啊
Hey, come on. You're breaking the fourth wall here.
听着  汉斯  不管你真名是什么
Listen, Hans, or whatever your name is,
看见那个女人了吗
you see that woman?
她是真的警察  真的有谋杀发生
She's a real cop. There's been a real murder,
而你真的是被关押了
and you are really under arrest.
你要是再不说实话  你就会待在监狱
If you don't start talking to us, you're gonna stay in jail...
真的监狱
Real jail.
你说这都是真的
You're telling me this is real?
千真万确
Very.
我真的是在监狱
I'm really in jail?
是的  你真的在监狱
Yes, you are really in jail.
不  不  我以为...
No, no, see--see I-I-- I thought that....
这不是体验的一部分吗
This isn't part of the experience?
什么体验
What experience?
那个公司叫做间谍大冒险
The company is called Spy-Ventures.
专为寻求刺激的人提供高端的间谍游戏
They specialize in high-end spy-cations for thrill seekers.
间谍游戏
Spy-cations?
如果你想要被绑架和审问
Yeah, you want to be kidnapped and interrogated?
他们有一套游戏  如果你想当间谍
They got a package. You want to be a super spy?
也有一套游戏  他们的口号就是"真实"
They got a package. Their motto is "Authenticity."
这就解释了海外账户
Right down to the offshore accounts,
假身份证明和仿真武器
false identifications and realistic weaponry.
好吧  找到负责人
All right. Find out who the hell's in charge.
让我们看看"真实"是不是包括谋杀
Let's see if "Authenticity" includes murder.
你还在躲吉娜吗
Are you still hiding from Gina?
我得承认  她很执着
She's persistent, I'll give her that.
你无法永远逃避  乖儿子
You can't outrun her forever, darling.
-我和她说吧  -不  不行
- Why don't I just talk to her?  - No! No!
不行  别
No, no, no.
好吧
All right.
这些夏日凉帽的再度出现
Does the reemergence of summer hats
是否意味着你将在汉普顿露面
mean you'll be making an appearance in the Hamptons?
哎  看起来你要独自一人度假了
Alas, you're going to have to stagger along without me.
我得到了那个角色
I got... the part!
太棒了
Fantastic!
-我为你骄傲  -谢谢  谢谢
- Oh-ho, I'm so proud!  - Thank you, thank you.
虽不是什么大角色
It's not the biggest role in the world,
但我喜欢夏令剧目
but I do love summer stock.
-你不会有事吧  -会有什么事
- You gonna be okay? - Why wouldn't I be?
我会一直待到八月份  阿丽克西斯也离开了
I'm gonna be gone through august, Alexis is away, and...
我不会有事的  我会把书写完
I'll be fine. I'll, uh... I'll finish the book.
-很好  -切特呢  他会孤独一人的
- Good. - What about Chet? He'll be all alone.
让他想念我也很好  我不想让他认为
It's good for him to miss me. I don't want him to assume...
我会永远待在他身边
that I'm gonna always just be around.
地方不错
Sweet place.
大家都在啊
Oh! Everyone's here.
打算独处吗
You were expecting to be alone?
没有  只是你回来早了  这是卡特
No, you're just home early. This is Carter.
他也要参加普林斯顿的项目
He's going to the princeton program, too.
-是吗  -见到你很高兴  卡特
- Is he now?  - Lovely to meet you, Carter.
我也是
Nice to meet you.
我会到厨房找你
Um... I'll meet you in the kitchen.
好的
Oh. Yeah.
我在项目网页上和他认识的
I friended him on the program page
碰巧他住在附近  所以我们打算见一见
And found out he lived nearby, so we decided to hook up.
我们觉得在那儿有熟人会比较顺利
We just thought it'd be nice to go there knowing someone,
再说他的房间在我的房间对面
and our rooms are right across from each other.
刚刚很抱歉
Hey, sorry about that...
你认为那男孩多大了
How old would you say that kid is?
和你干坏事的时候
Old enough to do all the things you did
年龄一样大
when you were his age.
正是我所担心的
That's what I'm afraid of.
忘了告诉你  詹姆斯·帕特森打过电话
Oh, I almost forgot to tell you. James Patterson called.
明天的纸牌游戏  他会晚点儿来
He's gonna be a little late for the poker game tomorrow.
很可能用那点时间再写一本书
Probably wants to use the time to write another book.
你上司不在太好了
Good thing your Captain's not here.
这也许会被当作不适宜的办公室行为
This might be construed as inappropriate office behavior.
待会儿见
I'll see you later.
好的
Yeah.
不是故意要打扰你们的美好时光
Didn't mean to break up your party.
没什么美好时光  我其实在等你
No, no party. I was actually waiting for you.
终于联络到了间谍大冒险的负责人
We finally got ahold of someone from Spy-Ventures.
经营者会在他们的办公室见我们
The owners are meeting us at their offices.
还有  你的前妻来电话了
Oh, yeah, and your ex-wife called.
她说你在躲她  因为你迟迟不把
She said that you've been avoiding her because you're late
《赤裸热浪》的手稿交给她
delivering your manuscript of... "Naked Heat."
名字很好记啊  你打算什么时候告诉我
That's a catchy title. When were you gonna tell me?
我在等恰当的时机
Well, I was waiting for the perfect time.
可是一直没等到
It just never happened.
她又在封面上裸体了  是吗
She's naked on the cover again, isn't she?
差不多  是的
Kinda, yeah.
太好了  "没人"会取笑我了
That's great. No one's gonna make fun of me.
还好
Good.
这是罗杰·法瑞戴
That's Roger Farraday.
他报名了一个四天的秘密游戏任务
He was on the 4-day covert ops package,
执行一项对联合国大使
culminating in a staged assassination
-的暗杀任务  -康涅狄格州  斯坦福市
- of a U.N. Diplomat. - Stamford, Connecticut.
他把他妻子梅琳达列为紧急联络人
He lists his wife Melinda as his emergency contact.
探长  我们...对造成的误会深表歉意
Detective. We're--we're very sorry about the confusion.
一收到你们的讯息我们就联络警局了
We called as soon as we got your messages.
假的身份证明和开曼群岛
So the fake IDs, the Cayman Islands--
是的  是体验的一部分
Yeah, they're all part of the experience.
你们绝对想不到
You have no idea how excited people get
他们必须用海外账户
when they have to
交款时是多么的兴奋
wire their payment to an offshore account.
你们的口号是"真实"
So your slogan is "Authenticity."
有没有可能是你们的一位顾客太当真了
Is it possible one of your other players took things too far?
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle, uh,
我们非常重视客户的安全
we take the safety of our guests very seriously.
虽然我们的武器以假乱真  但都合法且不能改装
Our weapons look real, but their legal, inoperable
并只能用于游戏
and rigged for game play.
所以如果其中一个客户杀了罗杰
So if one of the guests killed Roger,
他们一定用的自己的武器  不是我们的
They used their own weapon, not ours.
武器是假的  但钱是真的
So the weapons are fake, but the money is real?
什么钱
What money?
车里发现的五千欧元
The 5,000 euros we found in the car.
我们有时会有金钱交易
Uh... yeah, we--we do money drops sometimes,
但从不会用真钱
but never with real currency.
那会比他订的服务花的钱还多
That's more than he paid for his package.
-确定是真钱吗  -是的
- Are you sure it was real?  - Positive.
那天晚上法瑞戴先生在公园做什么
What was Mr. Farraday doing in the park that night?
-任务的一部分吗  -不  不是
- Was that a part of a mission?  - No, no, no.
公园里晚上做任务过于危险
The park is too dangerous to work at night.
他最后的任务应该死前几小时就结束了
And his last mission should've ended hours earlier.
最后的任务是什么
What was his last mission?
法瑞戴吗  对  我是他的管理员
Farraday? Yeah. I was his handler.
那天他最后的任务是公交站储物柜提取情报
His last mission that day was the bus locker drop.
十点时我检查过  空的
I checked it at 10:00. It was empty.
所以我们知道他拿到了那支笔
So we know he picked up the pen.
-有录音的那支笔  -是的
- The one with the recording?  - Yeah.
他昨天的任务是咖啡馆会面
His next activity was the cafe meet yesterday.
十点到午夜  他去哪里了呢
So where did he go between 10:00 and midnight?
他又是怎么带着五千欧元
And how did he end up in the park
跑到公园的呢
with 5,000 euros in his car?
他最后不是要做一个队友协作任务吗
Wasn't his last drop an accomplice mission?
队友协作任务
An accomplice mission?
有时  需要玩家一起完成任务
Well, sometimes we have players do tasks together,
而且不知道对方是友是敌
not knowing if the other is friend or foe.
他和代号145一起行动  法国特工
He was paired with designate 145, French Intelligence.
安德莉亚·费舍尔  如果她和他在一起
Andrea Fisher. If she was with him,
也许她知道他接着去哪里了
maybe she knows where he went next.
认出她了吗
Recognize her?
当然
Mais oui.
老天  你们一定觉得我在咖啡馆的举动
Oh, god. You both must think I'm so stupid,
非常蠢
the way that I acted in the cafe.
只是游戏的一部分嘛
All part of the game.
送给自己的假期  这是他们的口号
It's a vacation from yourself. That's what they say.
别误会
I mean, don't get me wrong. You know,
我爱我丈夫和孩子
I-I love my husband and my kids, but--
但每次普通度假  我依然是位母亲和妻子
but every time I go away, I'm-- I'm still a mom and a wife.
我丈夫说"如果你自己买单  就可以去"
My husband said, "If you can pay for it, you can go."
剪优惠券费神  但省下了不少生活费
So it took a lot of coupon clipping,
我终于当上了间谍
but I got to be a spy.
你和被害人很熟吗
Our victim... how well did you know him?
我们曾经一起执行了几个任务
We... had a couple of tasks together,
但我们都是在扮演角色
but--but we were always playing roles.
公车站任务时  你和法瑞戴先生一起吗
You were with Mr. Farraday when he did the bus station drop?
是的  我们破解了密码
Yeah. Yeah, we, uh, we cracked the code, and, um,
然后去取我们的包裹
we went to-- to get our packages.
你知道他的下一步吗
Do you know where he went next?
运送公文包
To deliver the briefcase.
公文包  怎样的公文包
Briefcase? What briefcase?
在储物柜里
It was in the locker.
我没有拿到  我就以为是他的额外任务
I-I didn't get one, so I assumed it was a bonus mission.
你知道公文包里装有什么吗
Do you know what was in the briefcase?
我不知道  你得问他们
I-I don't know. You have to ask them.
刚刚那是间谍大冒险的杰森
That was Jason from Spy-ventures.
储物柜里放的应该
The only thing that was supposed to be in that locker
只有一只钢笔  他亲手放进去的
was a pen set, which he put in there himself.
他不知道那公文包是哪里来的
He has no idea where that briefcase came from.
如果那钱和公文包
If the money and the briefcase
与游戏无关
weren't connected to the game,
也许这两者彼此有关系
maybe they're connected to each other.
被害人的妻子和生意伙伴
Victim's wife and business partner--
他们刚刚去认尸了
they just ID'ed the body.
你去查查公车站的储物柜
Can you check the lockers at the bus depot,
-看看是否在监控范围里  -好的
- see if they're covered by cameras?  - Yeah, sure.
请坐
Please take a seat.
我不想坐  他们说过很安全
I don't want to sit down. They said it was safe.
他们说过都是假的
They said it was all pretend.
我们还不肯定你丈夫的死
We can't be sure that your husband's death
是否与这游戏有关  法瑞戴夫人
had anything to do with the game, Mrs. Farraday.
你觉得谁会
Can you think of a reason
有理由伤害罗杰
someone would want to harm Roger?
罗杰是那种人见人爱的家伙
Roger was one of those guys everybody instantly liked.
所以他工作非常出色
Uh, that's why he was so good at his job.
我们共同拥有一家代理行  就在斯坦福市外
We owned a dealership together, just outside Stamford.
如果不讨人喜欢  你就卖不出去车
Can't sell cars if people don't like you.
还有谁知道他会在城里
Who else knew that he was gonna be in the city?
只有李和我
Just Lee and I.
八年了  探长
Eight years, Detective.
我们已经结婚八年了
We were married for eight years.
现在他死了
And now he's dead?
通常情况如果遭遇
You know, it used to be
中年危机
if you were gonna have a midlife crisis,
你会买一辆法拉利  找个新女友
You'd just buy a Ferrari, get a new girlfriend,
甚至去跳伞
even jump out of a plane.
在公园里被枪杀  钱留在车上
Shot in the park, money in his car--
让你好奇他还干了什么来自娱自乐
makes you wonder what else he did to get his jollies.
现在我们知道他的真正身份
Now that we know who he really is,
我已经让埃斯波西托查他的财产情况
I've asked Esposito to look into his financials.
也许我们可以发现赤字红旗
Maybe we'll see a red flag somewhere.
说到红旗
Oh, speaking of red flags.
你好  戴明
Hey, Demming.
你好  卡塞尔
Hey, Castle.
记得我跟你说过
So you know that little place
在阿斯伯利的那个地方
in Asbury I was telling you about,
就在我们的沙滩小屋的转角处
around the corner from our beach house?
他们刚好在周五有空房
Well, they just had a reservation open up on friday.
如果我们早点离开  可能赶得上
If we leave early enough, we could probably make it.
让我看看有没有时间  好吗
Yeah, um... will you let me check into it?
好的  稍后见
Great. I'll see you later.
沙滩小屋
Beach house?
原以为你周末工作
Thought you were working this weekend.
很抱歉  卡塞尔  我应该告诉你的
Yeah, I'm sorry, Castle. I shoulda just told you.
我只是不想因为汤姆和我在一起
I just didn't want things to be... awkward between us
让我们之间变得尴尬
now that Tom and I are... together.
不会  我明白
No, I get it. Yeah.
你只是想让你的私生活私密一些
No, you want your private life to be private.
是的  我只是不想大家
Yeah, I-I just don't-- I don't want anyone
感到不自在
to feel uncomfortable.
当然不会  我是说
No, of course not. No, I mean...
这样让我要说的话更容易说出口
actually, that makes what I was gonna say a little easier.
因为我的书期  我在想
Um... well, with my book due, I was thinking
现在是我们休息一下的好时间
it'd be a good time for us to take a break.
-休息  -是啊
- A break?  - Yeah. Well, god knows,
你肯定厌倦我天天围着你转
you gotta be tired of me following you around all the time,
而我也真的需要好好写写书了
and I really do need to get some work done.
我老妈和女儿都各有安排  我就想
With everyone gone, I figure, why not just
我为何不留在汉普顿
stay up in the Hamptons, you know?
-暂时远离城市  -要去多久呢
- Get away from the city for a while.  - Well, for how long?
至少这个夏天
The summer at least.
我想这会是我们最后一件案子
I thought this would be our last case.
嘿  我们
Hey. So, uh, we...
-没事吧  -好极了
- Everything okay?  - Great.
是的  很好  你们有什么发现
Yeah, fine. Uh, what'd you guys find?
公车站储物柜的监控录像
Surveillance stills from the bus locker.
那个长岛家庭主妇是对的
Your long island housewife was right.
罗杰在晚上将近10点的时候
Roger picked up the briefcase from locker 27-B
-从储物柜27-B拿了公文包  -很好
- shortly before 10:00 P.M.  - Great.
你不想知道谁放的吗
You don't want to know who put it in there?
想知道  抱歉
Oh, yeah. I'm sorry. Yeah.
那是间谍大冒险里罗杰的管理员
That's Roger's handler from Spy-Ventures.
他说这公文包不是游戏的一部分
He said the briefcase wasn't part of the game,
那为什么他要把公文包放进罗杰的储物柜呢
so why is he putting it in Roger's locker?
-他为什么说谎  -就是啊
- And why did he lie?  - Exactly.
公文包里有什么  雨果
What was in the briefcase, Hugo?
我们和你的老板谈过  雨果
We talked to your bosses, Hugo.
我们知道这不是游戏的一部分
We know it wasn't part of the game.
但你却让一位玩家
And yet, you had one of your players
去取公文包然后替你运送
pick it up and deliver it for you.
结果他死了
And he just happened to end up dead.
-我不知道  -你不知道什么
- I didn't know.  - You didn't know what?
原本没人会受伤的  我...
Look, no one was supposed to get hurt. I just...
我需要一个人去做交易
I needed someone to make the exchange.
公文包里有什么  雨果  毒品还是钱
What was in the briefcase, Hugo, drugs, money?
-身份证明  -身份证明
- IDs.  - IDs?
我工作涉及制作身份道具
Part of my job is to make the ID kits--
公司徽章  虚拟国家的护照
corporate badges, passports from nonexistent countries.
但利用杰森的设备  你也可以伪造
But with Jason's equipment, you can forge counterfeit IDs
真实国家的身份证明
for real countries, too.
但那是非法的
But it's illegal.
那也没有阻止你  对吧
But that didn't stop you, did it?
那你都卖给谁
So who did you sell to?
大学学生  大多数是想去买啤酒
College kids, mostly looking to buy beer.
然后你利用玩家完成交易
And then you used game players to make the drops.
这样就算有人被抓了  也无法指认我
So if anybody got busted, they couldn't identify me.
他们只是一群大学生
I mean, these are college kids.
就算他们被抓了还可以向祖母求情
They'd roll over on their grandmothers if they got caught.
直觉告诉我  罗杰不是被
Well, something tells me that Roger wasn't killed
一群未成年的大学生杀死的
by a group of underaged college kids.
最后这次的工作有些不同
No, this last job, it was different.
我知道我不该接的
I knew I shouldn't have taken it,
-但他们出价很高  -谁
- but they were paying so much money. - Who?
他们是乌克兰人  从网上找到我
They're Ukrainians. They found me on the internet.
他们急需护照
They said they needed passports.
我安排了罗杰去交易  取钱
I sent Roger to make the drop and pick up the money.
五千欧元
5,000 euros.
他以为这只是另一个任务
He thought it was just another mission.
不过之后肯定是出了问题
But something must have gone wrong.
交易完成之后  他打热线找我
After he made the drop, he called me on the hotline,
说他被一辆黑色轿车跟踪
said he was being followed by a dark sedan.
一辆黑色轿车  当时是几点
A dark sedan? And what time was this?
11:30左右
11:30-ish.
听着  玩这个游戏会让人产生妄想
Look, playing the game, it makes you paranoid.
我当时以为一切都是他的幻觉
So I just--I figured it was just his imagination.
所以我闪烁其词的答复了他
So I gave him the standard line about evasive maneuvers.
我不知道他真的被跟踪了
I didn't really think he was being followed.
没想到是真的
But he was.
接近半夜时他再次打来
He called again close to midnight
说他的身份暴露了
and said his cover had been blown.
我以为他在开我玩笑  就没理他
I thought he was messing with me, so I shined him on.
我把他撂在一边  结果害死了他
I shined him on, and now he's dead.
我一定是做错了什么
I must have done something wrong.
一定是弄混了护照或是...
I must have messed up the passports or s--
所以他们才会找上他  杀他灭口
and they came after him and they killed him.
那个公文包  他送去哪里了
The briefcase-- where did he deliver it to?
雨果  我需要那些乌克兰人的地址
Hugo, the Ukrainians, I need an address now.
安全
Clear!
让他们转身
Turn 'em around!
都给我站好  不要动
Get up there, now! Stay there! Stay there!
是群孩子
They're kids.
他们是乌克兰人  但只是学生
Yep. They're Ukrainians, but they're students.
他们在自己国家可以喝酒
They're used to being able to drink back home,
但在这里他们需要假的身份证才能买到酒
but they needed fake IDs to buy booze here.
他们在参与暑期项目的同学那
They got Hugo's information from another kid
-得知雨果的信息  -暑期项目
- in the summer program. - Summer program?
他们是哈德森大学暑期交换项目的
Yeah, they're part of the summer exchange program
-交换生  怎么了  -没什么
- at Hudson University. Why? - No reason.
总之  他们都没有黑色轿车
Anyway, none of them own a dark sedan,
而且看起来罗杰刚把假身份证交给他们
and seeing as how they all went out partying
他们就都去参加派对了
the moment Roger dropped off the IDs,
我想他们都不是凶手
it's doubtful any of them are our killer.
你真的认为他被跟踪了吗
You actually think he was being followed?
11:30打电话  不久后他就中枪了
Well, he calls at 11:30 and then just before he's shot.
车子坏了  他徒步跑进公园
His car is damaged. He runs on foot into the park.
感觉上他是想找一个藏身之处
Sounds to me like he was running away.
问题是躲谁呢
But from whom?
虽然我也很想帮你
Well, as much as I'd like to help you run down
查遍本市所有的黑色轿车
every dark sedan in the city,
但我要主持一场扑克游戏
I have a poker game to host.
明早见
See you in the morning.
再见
See ya.
这是卡塞尔的最后一案
So... Castle's last case, huh?
我和莱恩想为他办场小型欢送会
Ryan and I thought we'd do a little going away party.
他又不是一去不返
Yeah. Well, it's not like he's leaving forever.
你真这么想吗
You sure about that?
他一直围着你转是为了什么
Why do you think he's been following you around all this time?
为了做调查吗
What, research?
他的调查够他写五十本书
The guy has done enough research to write 50 books.
听着  不管理由是什么  我敢肯定
Look... whatever the reason is, I'm pretty sure
当中不包括看着你和别的男人在一起
it doesn't include watching you be with another guy.
间谍游戏中发生谋杀案
A murder in the middle of a spy game
没人知道来龙去脉
where nobody knows what's going on?
合我口味
I like that.
乌克兰人是一个很妙的转折
The Ukrainians are a nice twist.
现在赃银
So we've explained the money,
小玩意和公文包都解释得通
the gadgets and the briefcase.
唯一解释不通的是  他为何被杀
The only thing we can't explain--why was he killed?
或许是你们查错方向了
Maybe that's because you're looking in the wrong place.
帕特森  那你会从哪方面去查
All right, Patterson. Where would you look?
如果我是作者
If I was writing this,
谋杀案和间谍游戏其实完全无关
the murder would have nothing to do with the spy game
实际上游戏本身为凶手提供了行凶的机会
except that it gave the killer an opportunity to act.
因为游戏情节能完美掩藏他的行踪
Knowing that the trappings of the game would cover his tracks.
大概就是这套路
Which is pretty much what's happened.
里克  不管我们多费心去构思小说
Look, Rick, as much trouble as we go to with these novels,
能使人杀人  就只有三种原因
there's only three reasons to commit a murder--
-爱情  金钱和掩盖罪行  -科奈尔说得对
- Love, money and to cover up a crime. - Cannell's right.
我会花更多时间调查被害人
I'd spend more time looking at your victim
而不是调查这个游戏
and less time looking at the game.
个人而言  我会多花点时间写作
Personally, I'd spend more time writing
而不是跟着警察朋友东奔西跑
and less time hanging out with your cop friend.
里奇  说真的  一年只出一本书
I mean, really, Ricky, just one book a year?
里克  真有点少
Kinda thin, Rick.
比起为你提供灵感  她更能让你分心
She seems like more of a distraction than a muse.
你们说得对
No, you're right.
我想我从这段关系中
I think I've gotten everything I can get
已经得到了我想要的一切
out of that relationship anyway.
可以走了吗
Hey. You ready?
-早  -早
- Hey. - Hey.
我刚刚在想...
I was just thinking...
-可以坐下吗  -坐吧
- May-- - Yeah.
我一直在想
I've been thinking...
我们可能查错方向了
maybe we're looking in the wrong place.
谋杀案可能和游戏完全无关
Maybe the murder has nothing to do with the game.
游戏只是为凶手提供了一个行凶的机会
Maybe it just afforded the killer an opportunity to act.
真是太巧了
That's so f-funny,
因为今天一早起来
because I was thinking the same thing
我也一直在想这事
when I woke up this morning,
可能我们过于关注游戏这条线
that maybe we got so caught up in the game
而忽略了至关重要的线索
that we stopped looking at what really mattered.
被害人
The victim.
正是  看看这个
Exactly. So check this out.
他的财政状况很正常
His financials came back clean.
后来我们调查了
But then we did a search on
他的合伙人李·科普里
his business partner, Lee Copley,
发现他两个月前申请了破产
and it turns out that he filed for bankruptcy two months
他以房地产抵押也还不清
ago overextended himself in real estate.
我猜猜  若罗杰死了
Let me guess, if Roger dies,
他拥有的那一半公司财产就归科普里了
his half of the business goes to Copley.
价值超过五十万美元
Over half a million dollars worth.
他妻子说过  知道罗杰在市区的
His wife did say, the only two people who knew
就她和科普里两个人
Roger was in the city were her and Copley.
猜猜科普里开的什么车
And guess what Copley drives.
黑色轿车
A dark Sedan?
罗杰是我的朋友  我们一起长大
Roger was my friend. We grew up together.
我为什么要杀他
Why would I kill him?
我可以告诉你"五十万"个理由
I can give you half a million reasons why.
怎么  就因为我面临财政问题吗
What, because I'm having financial problems?
就因为我们恰好一起做生意
Because we just happen to own a business together?
因为贪婪  科普里先生  那是最单纯的动机
Greed, Mr. Copley. It's the purest motive there is.
简直太荒谬了
Oh, this is ridiculous.
罗杰·法瑞戴遇害那晚
Where were you the night
你在哪儿
that Roger Farraday was murdered?
我在家睡觉
I was home in bed.
是吗  那你能解释下这个吗
Really? Then do you care to explain these?
这些照片是那晚八点
These are photos of you leaving your apartment garage
你离开公寓车库时拍到的
at 8:00 the night that he was murdered.
而这些是你第二天早上七点
And these are photos of you returning
返回时的照片
the following morning at 7:00 a.m.
"在家睡觉"算是露馅了
Kind of blows a hole in your whole "Home in bed" thing.
你撒谎了  科普里先生
You lied to me, Mr. Copley.
想要更改你的证词吗
Do you care to revise your statement?
晚上八点  你有足够的时间
8:00 p.m. That's plenty of time
从斯坦福开车过来
to drive to the city from Stamford.
你干了些什么  李
What did you do, Lee?
在旅馆守候  跟踪  直到他落单
Wait for him at the hotel, follow him till he was alone?
-不  我没有  -然后拿游戏当幌子
- No, I didn't.  - And then you used the game as cover.
不  听我说  我发誓  不是我干的
No. Look, I swear, I didn't do it.
是啊  你"在家睡觉"呢
Right. You were at home in bed.
不  我不在家  但我确实在睡觉
No, I wasn't... at home, but I was in bed...
和他老婆一起
With his wife.
抱歉  你说什么
I'm sorry. What?
我和罗杰的老婆睡在一起
I was in bed with Roger's wife.
我再确认一下
Let me-- let me get this straight.
你的不在场证据是  你在和
You-your alibi for killing your friend is you were
朋友的老婆上床
doing his-- his wife?
是的
Yeah.
怎么  你想让我认错吗
What? You want me to say I'm sorry?
想让我觉得难堪吗  我才不会
You want me to be embarrassed? I'm not.
你知道我和罗杰有多久没做爱了吗
Do you know how long it had been since Roger and I made love?
他只关心工作和那个破游戏
All he cared about was work and his extreme vacations.
没错  我是在和李幽会
So, yeah, I was seeing Lee.
那晚我确实和他在一起
Yeah, I was with him that night.
既然婚姻那么糟糕  为什么不离婚呢
Well, if things were that bad, why not just get a divorce?
你说笑吧  我可舍不得我的房子
Are you serious? My house is too nice.
难怪罗杰要找点别的乐子了
I can see why Roger needed a little extra fantasy in his life.
我问过他妻子的邻居了
I talked to the wife's neighbors.
有几个人见到李的车
A few of them remember Lee's car outside
-那晚停在她家外面  -那也不能说明什么啊
- the house that night.  - Well, that doesn't mean anything.
那家伙是个汽车经销商
The guy runs an auto dealership.
他可以中途换车
He could've just switched cars.
没错  但那天晚上很热
True, except it was a warm night,
-热到必须开窗  -不会吧
- Warm enough to leave the windows open.  - Oh, no.
错不了  她隔壁的邻居清楚地记得
Oh, yes. The next-door neighbor distinctly remembers
听到从她卧室的窗户传来的
hearing the sounds of loud, passionate lovemaking
响亮而激情四溢的做爱声
coming from the open bedroom window.
-吵得他午夜后才睡着  -我不相信
- Kept him up till well past midnight.  - I don't buy it.
他们都有杀人动机
They both had motive.
他们有奸情
They were having an affair.
又知道被害者身在何处
They knew exactly where he was.
就算有不在场证明
Just because they had an alibi
也不能摆脱嫌疑
does not mean they didn't do it.
你觉得他们雇了个杀手吗
Do you think they hired someone?
职业杀手的手法都明摆着呢
It had all the hallmarks of a professional hit.
肯定不是李干的  除非破产法庭
Well, it couldn't have been Lee unless he asked
允许他雇一位职业杀手
the bankruptcy court for permission to hire a hit man,
那是不可能的
And I don't think that's likely.
法瑞戴账户上唯一一笔异常支出
And the only unusual charge on the Farradays' account
是罗杰在开曼群岛
was the 10 grand that Roger wired to
转给间谍大冒险的1万美元
the Spy-Ventures account in the cayman islands.
1万美元
10 grand?
是啊  怎么啦
Yeah, why?
他只需付一半左右的费用
Because he only should've paid half that much.
记得间谍大冒险那个女人对我们
Do you remember what the woman at Spy-Ventures
在车里找到钱是怎么说的吗
said about the money we found in the car?
记得  她说五千欧元比
Yeah, that 5,000 euros was more than
他付的整个游戏费用要多
what he paid for his entire spy-cation.
他的银行账单显示他转了
His bank statement indicates he transferred
两笔五千美元的费用给那个公司
2 payments of 5 grand each to the game,
总共是一万美元
for a total of $10,000.
是同时付款的
The payments were made at the same time,
像是付了两次
almost like he paid twice.
若数据正确的话  他确实是付了两次款
If these numbers are correct, he did pay twice--
一次为自己  第二次为另一个玩家
Once for him, once for another player.
另一个玩家
Another player?
那个玩家是谁
Who was the other player?
安德莉亚·费舍尔
Andrea Fisher.
长岛的那个主妇
Our Long Island housewife?
她说在组队玩游戏前
She said she never met Roger
从未见过罗杰
until they were teamed up for the game.
若从未见过  他为什么替她付钱呢
Well, if they never met, why did he pay for her?
肯定是搞错了
There must be some mistake.
我们和银行核对过了  费舍尔太太
We checked with the bank, Mrs. Fisher.
绝对没错
There is no mistake.
你没有向间谍大冒险付过款
You never paid Spy-Ventures.
是罗杰付的
But Roger did.
不过优惠券那个借口不错
The coupon clipping was a nice touch, though.
是用来糊弄你丈夫的吧
I assume that was for your husband's benefit?
你和罗杰·法瑞戴到底是什么关系
What was the nature of your relationship with Roger Farraday?
我们是
We were, um...
朋友
friends.
你们什么时候认识的
When did the two of you first meet?
去年
Last year.
我带女儿谢尔比
I was, uh, I was taking my daughter Shelby
到市区去上舞蹈班
into, uh, the city for dance classes.
送完她后  我会去博物馆
After I dropped her off, I'd go to the museum.
每个星期  我都会看到他
Every week, I'd see him,
站在莫奈的《睡莲》前
standing in front of Monet's "Water lilies."
那一个小时  没人对我说"妈妈干这个"
You know, for an hour, it wasn't "Mommy can you do this"
或"亲爱的干那个"  我是我自己
or "Honey can you do that." You know, I was me.
但是  几个星期后
Oh, god. After a few weeks,
从博物馆见面变成了旅馆幽会
the museum turned into a hotel.
接着  谢尔比的舞蹈课也结束了
And... then Shelby's dance classes ended.
你再没有理由到市区去了
You had no excuse to go into the city anymore.
初次见面时  我们装作是间谍
When we first met, we pretended to be spies,
在博物馆交换秘密
exchanging secrets at the museum.
罗杰就想  为何不来一场真实的间谍冒险呢
Roger thought, why not have a real-life spy adventure?
那样我们还有最后一次机会在一起
And we could have one last time together.
亲爱的  我回来了
Hey, hon. I'm back.
天哪  求你们别告诉我丈夫
Oh, my god. Please don't tell my husband.
没这个必要  费舍尔太太
We don't have to, Mrs. Fisher.
他已经知道了
He already knows.
怎么回事
What's going on?
费舍尔先生  我是凯特·贝克特探长
Mr. Fisher, I'm Detective Kate Beckett.
纽约警察局的
NYPD.
这到底是怎么回事
What's this about?
你是否有辆09年的四门黑色轿车
You own a black 2009 4-door sedan?
是的  为什么问
Yeah. Why?
-车在哪里  -在修理店
- Where is it? - It's in the shop.
我离开超市时车撞到柱子
I hit a pole while I was backing out at the supermarket.
你作为射击手  可强过说谎许多
You're a much better shot than you are a liar.
你的枪在纽约州有持枪登记
The state of New York lists you as a registered gun owner--
格洛克点45
Glock 45.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
上帝啊  你对他做了什么
Oh, my god. What did you do to him?
他罪有应得
What he deserved.
上帝啊
Oh, my god.
罗杰那晚觉得被跟踪是正确的
So Roger was right about being followed that night.
当这位丈夫发现妻子的婚外情后
Well, when the husband got on to the affair,
他也来了场间谍游戏
he did a little spy game of his own--
追踪并杀害了他妻子的情人
Tracked down and killed his wife's lover.
两桩婚外情  无爱的婚姻
Two affairs, a loveless marriage...
有个男人因此丧命真悲哀  只因所有相关当事人
It's sad a man had to die because all the people involved
都害怕说出真实的感觉
were too scared to say what they really felt.
是的  是很悲哀
Yes, it is sad.
这种演出能有多少
And how many shows like that?
当然  两张票  说定了  好的
Sure. Well, make it two, and you got a deal. All right.
我得走了  要送阿丽克西斯去普林斯顿
Hey, I gotta run. I gotta drive Alexis to Princeton.
但我会准时赶回来参加兄弟们
But I will be back in time for that little surprise party
为我举行的惊喜派对  怎么了
the boys are throwing for me-- what? What?
没什么
Nothing.
好的  回见了
Okay. I'll see you.
你还有家当留在家吗
Is there anything you're not bringing?
你  你确定一个人没事吗
You. Are you sure you're gonna be okay?
这可是你第一次独自待这么长时间
This is the first time you've ever been alone this long.
这句话应该是我对你说
I'm supposed to be saying that to you.
而且  我可不会孤单太久
And besides, I might not be alone for very long.
-你邀请了某人吗 -一开始她回绝了
- You invited someone? - She said no at first,but
但我觉得她会来的
I got a feeling she'll come around.
这位某人我认识吗
Oh. Is it anyone I know?
我可不是大嘴巴
I don't kiss and tell.
看来这个夏天"走运"的可不止我一个
It looks like I'm not the only one who's getting lucky this summer.
开玩笑  开玩笑
Kidding. Kidding.
我只是  只是开玩笑
I'm just--I'm just kidding.
一点也不好笑  真是一点也不好笑
That's not funny. Oh, that's so not funny.
我们说的不仅仅是这个周末  对吗
It's not just this weekend we're talking about, is it?
不是
No.
凯特  是我说错了什么吗
Was it something I said, Kate?
还是做错了什么
Or something I did?
不  你很好
No. You're great.
你真的很好  我也很喜欢你
You're really great, and I really like you.
只是  我觉得
It's just, I don't think
这不是我现在想要的
that this is what I'm looking for right now.
凯特  你想要什么
Well, what is it you're looking for, Kate?
那场景太伤感了
It was very emotional.
泪眼汪汪
Yeah, there were a lot of tears.
阿丽克西斯倒是一点也不伤心
Um, Alexis was fine, by the way.
听我说  卡塞尔
I gotta say, Castle,
我们一定会想念你在这里的日子
we're gonna miss you around here.
我也会想念你们
Yeah, I'm gonna miss you,too.
但你会把咖啡机留下  是吧
You're still leaving the coffee machine,  though, right?
我不在但不能让你受罪啊
I can't have you suffer in my absence.
停尸间也用得上一台
Oh, we could really use one of those down in the morgue.
卡塞尔离开后  希望我们的破案率别下降
With Castle gone, I just hope our clearance rate doesn't drop.
看看谁收工了
Oh! Look who's off duty.
是的  卡塞尔  我也有下班的时候
Yeah, well, Castle, I'm not all work.
别和她拼酒
Don't get into a drinking contest with her.
-她稳赢你  -谢谢
- She can take you. - Thank you.
不喝酒我也可以赢他
Oh, I don't need to drink to take him.
你这是咋啦
Ooh! What's gotten into you?
卡塞尔  单独聊会?
Castle, do you have a second?
当然没问题
Of course. Yeah.
怎么了
What's up?
我想说  我知道自己
Look... I know that I'm not
不是容易了解的人
the easiest person to get to know,
而且  我的想法也经常没有表露出来
and... I don't always let on what's on my mind.
但这过去的一年  与你合作
But... this past year, working with you...
我很开心
I've had a really good time.
我也是
Yeah. Me,too.
我要说的是...
So I'm--I'm just gonna say this and--
理查德  准备好了吗
Richard... you ready?
你来啦  吉娜
Hey, Gina.
-贝克特  你还记得我的前妻吉娜吗  -兼出版商
- Beckett, you remember Gina,my ex-wife. - And publisher.
-是的  -我们通过电话
- Yes. - Yeah,we spoke the other day.
-看来你终于逮到他了  -是啊
- Looks like you finally tracked him down. - Oh,yeah.
有时候他完全就是个小孩子
He's such a little boy sometimes.
我也不知道为什么  其实孩子气不太对我胃口
I mean, I don't know why. It's not like I bite... much.
我们应该出发了
Well, we better get going
-否则整晚都会塞车  -出发?
- or we're gonna be stuck in traffic all night. - Going?
-去汉普顿  -度周末吗
- To the Hamptons. - For the weekend?
不是  整个夏天
No, for the summer, actually.
这样他可以在我眼皮下把书写完
So I can stay on top of him while he finishes his book.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
我不知道你们和好了
I-I didn't think the two of you got along.
本来没有  但昨晚在电话中
We didn't. But then last night on the phone,
我们开始聊
we started talking...
-最后聊了几个小时  -是的
- And we ended up talking for hours. - Yeah.
-一如从前  -是的
- Just like old times. - Yeah.
那个
So...
抱歉
I'm sorry.
你准备对我说什么
You were, uh, you were telling me something.
我准备说  祝你们这个夏天愉快
Yeah, I wanted to say, have a great summer.
也祝你愉快
You, too.
正如你所说
A-and like you said,
与你合作  真的真的很开心
it's-- it's been really, really great.
是  很开心
Yeah... it has.
秋天再见吗
See you in the fall?
秋天再见
See you in the fall.